ANGEL COCHACHEZ

acochachez@gmail.com · 510-829-4019 · Github: https://github.com/codifyme
Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/angel-cochachez/ · Portfolio: https://acthefullstackdev.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with over 3 years of experience focused on Front End and Back End Development. Graduated from the UC Berkeley Extension Full Stack Coding Boot Camp and developed responsive websites and mobile first design. As a team leader, I have been responsible for running multiple projects and determining how various parts of the project should be prioritized with team members. My practical experience includes Mobile App Development, which encompasses testing during the full development cycle, analyzing its performance with the development team for feedback and meeting high-quality standards before publishing.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.Js, Express, JavaScript, JQuery, JSON, React.js, React Native, GIT, GitHub, Mongo DB, MySQL, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, Docker, GraphQL, JavaScript Web APIs and several other languages.

PROJECTS

Show Me Around | Show Me Around is an App that provides preliminary tour guidance and information about places being visited. This project comes across with a simple user interface enabling the user to search their favorite places using a search engine (google maps) that will render all relevant pictures to the searched topic.

Technologies Used: Javascript, Jquery, HTML, CSS and API Documentations and Sources for Open Weather Map (Geolocation), Pixabay (pictures), AccuWeather (weather forecasts), Unsplash (JSON API) and Google Maps API.

Heroku (https://nanotelegram.github.io/showmearound/)| Github (https://github.com/nanotelegram/showmearound)

Un-Productive | (Un||Productive) is a React App that can be used to look up for books (Productive), or video games (||) (Un-Productive) based on the title of user inputs in a search bar.

Technologies Used: This is a full MERN stack application that uses NodeJS/React Router Dom, Redux, and Axios for the server and routing, MYSQL for the database coming from the local and remote DB.

Heroku (https://un-productive.herokuapp.com/)| GitHub(https://github.com/vic30004/un-productive-)

Find My Food Truck | Provides real time locations for food trucks in the San Francisco Area using API data

Technologies Used: MERN stack application that uses NodeJS/React Router Dom, Redux, and Axios for the server and routing,
MongoDB/Mongoose for the database coming from the local and remote DB on the Back End and Materialize CSS framework
on the Front End. The App is a multifunctional Application that comes with a Recipe Finder App integrated that will render all
relevant exotic recipes and Food Truck Finder that use a search engine (google maps) that will render real time location for
food trucks in the San Francisco Area.

Heroku (https://nom-nom-baa86.firebaseapp.com/) | GitHub (https://github.com/codifyme/find-my-food-truck)

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER ZIGGURAT TECHNOLOGIES, INC

OCT 2020 - DEC 2020

Berkeley

Berkeley

Worked on a variety of projects regarding the company Full Stack Web Development for web and App Designs.

- Expertise in Web development using JavaScript/jQuery , JSON, React, Front-end JS Frameworks and HTML.
 - Developed the company financial stock market data API that helps developers to build scale financial applications.
 - Created a user authentication with Firebase verification(private route and pages) using React Hooks and Redux.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER CODE WITH CORGIS

JULY 2019 - OCT 2020

- Accurately translating client requirements and needs into application designs and systems developments.
 Built Single page React and React Native applications for startups and small companies.
- Responsible for taking a design and turning it into a beautiful user experience using React, React Native, Redux, GraphQL, NodeJS, Git/Github, Backend APIs, along with other libraries and frameworks.
- Helped the companies understand their product from a user and business perspective while developing the product.

• Use the responsive utilities of the Bootstrap frameworks to facilitate the design displaying properly on different devices.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER AUG 2016 – PRESENT CONSULTANT Berkeley

Worked on a range of freelance web applications using full MERN Stack open sources for personal projects and client websites.

- Deployed multiple React Apps that use Express (API Routes), Handlebars, Axios, Sequelize, Mongoose and many more
 other dependencies that implement and integrate React App into the frontend application based on the project
 requirements and framework structure.
- Used MySQL and MongoDB to query a remote database stored in the server and render results returned by SQL or pictorials, graphs or complex results (DB Tables) at medium scale.
- Built scalable APIs using JavaScript to fetch and render any record detail and secured APIs through authorization.
- Performed Heroku deployments with Git and Node.JS to develop a fast and scalable network application; which is perfect for data-intensive real-time applications that run across and perform in multiple devices.
- Heroku (https://github.com/codifyme/movieinfo)
- Heroku (Coming soon | GitHub(https://codifyme.github.io/clicky-game/)

FRONT END DEVELOPER TINITA'S EVENTS, FLORIST

JUNE 2013-DEC 2017 El Cerrito

Worked on the company's new landing page (https://tinitaevents.wixsite.com/tinitaevents) design, framework and graphic design for latest Bay Area Wedding Fairs events and bridal shows such as; photo galleries, flower decorations, contact info and more.

- Contributed to and regularly updated the company's social media network to increase merchandise sales and popularity by 20%.
- Worked closely with the project manager and floral design team to ensure we were fully leveraging the website for maximum impact/results.
- Booked events for local wedding fair's and tour announcements using our social media channel and local newspapers.
- Implemented Google Analytic and social media channels to keep analytic records of the audience and target business advertising to increase the website traffic.

FRONT END DEVELOPER, FOUNDER ROCK SUR

JAN 2013 - DEC 2016

Oakland

Coordinated with six of the most popular Latin American Rock Bands in the Bay Area and helped them to introduce their music to the Latino Community using the company website and social media channels.

- Developed landing page utilizing Wix platform and framework cross-device access with the purpose of supporting Latin American Rock Bands and their Music in the Bay Area (https://rocksur.wixsite.com/sfrocksur).
- Booked events for local concerts and tour announcements using the company's social media channel.
- Embedded YouTube Videos (Custom video generator) in HTML and made it responsive on any sized device.
- Linked MP3 music files from the artists' band sites using (SoundCloud and Bandcamp) to the website.

FRONT END DEVELOPER OCTAGON CONSULTING, APOLLO

JUNE 2009 - JULY 2010

EL Cerrito

Contributed to building the company's new website and was responsible for working on front-end work, mobile responsiveness, layout integration with theme framework, adjusting CSS classes and styling components.

- Implemented Google Analytic and Social Media channels in order to increase website traffic.
- Used Filezilla to transfer files between client websites and remote server over the internet in the most efficient way.
- Used Cpanel hosting control panel to manage client websites from a web based interface to store files, backup database and update MySQL database. For more info please see the company website.

EDUCATION

Certificate: Full Stack Development, UC BERKELEY EXTENSION, BERKELEY CODING BOOTCAMP JUNE-DEC 2019

Completion: FRONT END DEVELOPMENT, CODIFY ACADEMY WEB DEVELOPMENT JUNE - DEC 2016

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration, CAL STATE UNIVERSITY EAST BAY JULY 2008 - JUNE 2011